# 小豬
Piggy!
# 你在這裡幹嘛
What are you doing here?
# 在曬太陽嗎
Are you sunbathing?
# 現在太陽又沒有
But the sun is not shining now.
# 這條公豬很兇的 這條公豬
This boar is really fierce, this boar.
# 它還發脾氣 發脾氣竟然還交人哦 (註︰語序關係，把重覆部份換了一下)
It bites, it even bites if it loses temper.
# 是不是
Don't you?
# 不可以咬我知不知道
You should never bite me, got it?
# 咬了我的話
If you ever dare to bite me,
# 我就把你給宰啦
I would kill you.
# 你看 這條公豬
Have a look at this boar!
# 它的腳趾是白的哦
It has white toes, see?
# 身上好多泥巴呀
It's covered with mud.
# 天氣熱得話 它會搞到泥巴上去
It always gets onto the mud when it's hot,
# 抓癢癢 那蟲子啊 蚊子啊 就咬不進它
to scratch the itch, and to prevent the bites from, you know, the bugs, and the mosquitoes.
# 皮也很厚
It has really thick skin too.
# 它現在應該一百多斤
I think it's now around, sixty, seventy,
# 一百五十斤左右 (註︰不想太麻煩註釋「斤」，把說法改一改較好看)
or seventy five kilograms.
# 還不夠胖 要把它養到五百斤
It's not fat enough. I wanna make it two hundred and fifty kilograms,
# 胖成一條豬一樣
so that it becomes as fat as a pig.
# 本來就是豬
Well, it's already a pig from day one.
# 胖成一條牛一樣
Then as fat as a cow
# 你看 它的耳朵
Look! Its ears...
# 你的耳朵用來做那個
Your ears can be made into a, um,
# 涼拌耳朵很好吃的哦
cold and dressed ears. It would be really tasty.
# 它的 腿
Its...legs,
# 後腳 後腳用來做紅燒 (註︰我想他是想說「後腿」，但似乎和粵語一樣，腿腳不分)
the hind legs, the hind legs can be braised.
# 排骨用來做紅燒排骨
And the ribs, the ribs can be braised,
# 也可以烤
or grilled.
# 很好吃的
Tasty!
# 前腳就用來煲湯
A soup can be made using the forelegs.
# 那個
And then,
# 身上的肉哇
the pork on the body,
# 用來做
can be,
# 用來做那個
can be, you know,
# 炒芹菜
can be fried with celery.
# 特別是它豬肚 (註︰不明白怎麼「特別是」，不理了，直譯算了)
Especially its stomach,
# 豬肚煲雞
when stewed with chicken,
# 很補的
it's good for health.
# 到時候我殺了豬之後哇 我就搞個豬 豬雜湯
I would make a pork, pork offal soup, after slaughtering the pig.
# 就是 豬肝跟瘦肉跟豬腸混在一起 煮一鍋湯 (註︰語序長短關係，放在一起較好辦)
It's like, making a soup with the liver, lean meat, guts, everything together.
# 還小的時候每家每戶殺豬的時候哇
When I was a kid, this pork offal soup was always on the table,
# 都要吃這個豬雜湯
whenever a pig was slaughtered.
# 全村人一起吃哦
It was shared with everybody in the village.
# 等於說全村人去幫忙殺一條豬
That means, it took the whole village to slaughter a pig.
# 然後就是 煮一餐肉
And then we made a feast,
# 煮一餐那個豬肉宴大家一起吃
made a feast with the pork and enjoyed together.
# 現在 現在農村
Now, now in the villages,
# 都幾乎都看不到殺豬哇 都是進屠宰場
slaughtering of pigs is rarely seen. It's done in a slaughterhouse instead.
# 哇 這個蹄子
Wa! The hoof,
# 這個蹄子用來
the hoof should be,
# 紅燒一下挺好吃
should be really tasty if it's braised.
# 干嘛
What happens?
# 哎呀
Aya!
# 我又沒說好
I didn't even mention you.
# 生氣了一樣 你看
It looks angry. Look!
# 生氣了啦
Yea, it's angry,
# 想跑
and wants to run away.
# 你看 它的那個 前臂
Look! Its ah, it's forearm,
# 好多肉哇
is so meaty!
# 刮下來全是肉
It's covered with meat.